Farnsboro Tenants Association 031
People's Archive, MLK Library
Farnsboro Tenants Association Records
1972-1978
People's Archive, MLK Library
Farnsboro Tenants Association
031
2 Linear feet
5 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: General Alphabetical Files, 1975-1978 (1 linear ft.) This series contains topical files arranged alphabetically. It includes, financial and administrative materials, meeting minutes and notes, member lists, clippings, and rental information. Much of the material concerns rent increases, maintenance problems and inspections, and the condominium conversion of the building. Series 2: Legal and Governmental Materials, 1975-1978 (.50 linear ft.) This series includes housing and landlord-tenant regulations, Advisory Neighborhood Commission (ANC) newsletters, legal notes, and exhibits prepared or compiled by Farnsboro tenants for litigation involving rents, property maintenance, and condo conversion. The folders are arranged alphabetically. Series 3: Petitions 1976-1978 (.25 linear ft.) This series includes petitions filed by the tenants regarding rental rollbacks for maintenance problems, the condominium conversion, and individual rental increases filed with the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of petition, then chronologically. Series 4: Correspondence 1975-1978 (.25 linear ft.) This series contains correspondence and related documents, largely to the landlord and the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by type, then chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
The Farnsboro is located at 2129 Florida Avenue NW, and was converted to condominiums in the late 1970s. The Tenants Association was formed in 1975 to negotiate with the landlord, Lester Carpenter Leonard, regarding rents and maintenance problems at the building. Later the tenants contested the conversion of the building to a condominium and the eviction of renters.
Custodial History
The collection was donated to the Library in 1991 by Sidney S. Williston.
Related Materials
Collection 006: Washington Housing Association Records (1953-1961)
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of materials produced and obtained by the Farnsboro Tenants Association. It includes clippings, newsletters, petitions, meeting minutes, and correspondence.
Housing; Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; Tenants' associations; Organizational Records; Correspondence; Legal documents; Sheridan-Kalorama (Washington, D.C.)
- Series 1: General Alphabetical Files, 1975-1978
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains topical files arranged alphabetically. It includes, financial and administrative materials, meeting minutes and notes, member lists, clippings, and rental information. Much of the material concerns rent increases, maintenance problems and inspections, and the condominium conversion of the building.
  - Administrative materials, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Apartment 201 Detail, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Apartment 201 - Letters to and from Lester Leonard, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Application to convert to condominiums, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Building buy cooperative or condominium, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bulletin Board Material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Condominium Cafe, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Condominium conversion press file, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Condominium protest, June 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Decatur Associates, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - District Capital Corporation, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Emergency Committee to save rental housing, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Final accounting, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Genesis and member information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Inspections, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Maintenance problems, 1957, 1971-1973, 1976-78 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meetings, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meeting notes and other administrative papers, October 1975-December 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Meeting notes and other administrative papers, March-July 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Meeting notes and other administrative papers, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Meeting notes and other administrative papers, October 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Meeting notes and other administrative papers, November 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Member and tenant lists, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Members, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and attendance lists, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Permission to be Inspected and Questionnaire, February 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - PG and E, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Purchase Agreement, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Registration, October 29 1975 and March 13 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Registration analysis, October 29 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Registration, March 30 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Rental information, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rents, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rent advice, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rent increases, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rent information, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rent refunds, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Responses to questionnaire violations, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Settlement agreement, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tenant forms, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Tenant matters, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Tenant purchasing data, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series 2: Legal and Governmental Materials, 1975-1978
  Includes housing and landlord-tenant regulations, ANC newsletters, legal notes, and exhibits prepared or compiled by Farnsboro tenants for litigation involving rents, property maintenance, and condo conversion of Farnsboro. The folders are arranged alphabetically.
  - ANC, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ANC newsletters, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Exhibits, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Housing code violations, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Housing regulations no. 19-23 change, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Landlord tenant regulations and forms, 1975-1978 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lawyers, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Legal assistance, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Legal notes, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Legal Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Regulations of the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission, April 26 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Regulations of the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Regulations of the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Petitions 1976-1978
  Includes petitions filed by the tenants regarding rental rollbacks for maintenance problems, the condominium conversion, and individual rental increases filed with the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of petition, then chronologically.
  - Allied tenant petitions, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Condominium conversion petition, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Rental accommodations petitions, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rental accommodations petitions, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rental accommodations petitions, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tenant petition 164, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Tenant petition 1034, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Tenant petitions (6 folders), 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series 4: Correspondence 1975-1978
  Contains correspondence and related documents, largely to the landlord and the D.C. Rental Accommodations Commission. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by type and then chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence re problems, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re problems, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Duplicate correspondence and other documents, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Duplicate correspondence and other documents, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tenant correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)